Guide to the Manuel and Carmen Paredes letters and scrapbooks MS 971
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Manuel and Carmen Paredes letters and scrapbooks
1947-1953
1977-1979
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Hauge, Ruby
MS 971
1 Linear Feet (2 boxes)
This collection contains correspondence and scrapbooks written and assembled by Manuel Paredes.
Biographical / Historical
Manuel Paredes was born in Arequipa, Peru on May 29, 1924. After college, he became a Petroleum Geologist, working in oil exploration in Peruvian Amazonia from the late 1940s to the early 1950s. During this time, he wrote letters to Carmen Amado Nuñez, his childhood friend in Lima. In 1952, they were married.
After doing graduate work at Stanford University, Manuel Paredes lived between Peru and the United States. The Paredes family moved to Houston in 1976. Manuel Paredes passed away on April 22, 2002. Carmen Paredes passed away on January 18, 2021.
Content Description
This collection contains mainly letters written by Manuel Paredes to Carmen Amado, who became his wife. There are also photographs and scrapbooks of his oil exploration in Peruvian Amazonia.
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
This material is open for research.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Ruby Hauge April 2021.
Index Terms
Subjects
Oil and gas; Indigenous peoples
Places
Peru
Subjects (Persons)
Hauge, Ruby
- Series I: Correspondence
  - Cards, 1955 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1951-01-1951-03 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1951-04-1951-06 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1951-07-1951-09 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1951-10-1951-12 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1952-01-1952-02 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 1952-03-1952-04 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 1952-05-1952-06 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1952-07-1952-08 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1952-09-1952-12 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1953 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1977-1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, other, 1951 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Series II: Ephemera, Photographs, and Scrapbooks
  - Ephemera, 1955 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Photographs, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Scrapbook, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbooks, 1947-1953 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Scrapbook, 1951-1953 (Box 2, Folder 9)